Rashed Ahmed Rahat

Address: Road 20, House 38, Nikunja 2, Dhaka 1229

Mobile: 01633179767

Email: imrashedrahat@gmail.com

Portfolio Site: rashedrahat.github.io/rashedrahat.me

GitHub: www.github.com/rashedrahat

Stack Overflow: stackoverflow.com/users/10427807/rashedrahat

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/rashedrahat



SUMMARY

Performance-driven and motivated Full-Stack Web Developer with 2 years of extensive experience in web design and web development. Adept to achieve extraordinary results. Possess a strong attention to detail, well-developed time management skills, and ability to complete all projects within schedule and in a timely manner.

WORK EXPERIENCE

(Jun. 2019 – Present) Junior Software Engineer, Workspace Infotech Limited, Dhaka Bangladesh

- Developed a web application, "WebSMS", for marketing brands. <u>Bootstrap</u> was used to develop the front end which includes chat, sending whatsapp and normal messages and variety of advanced features. The backend, built using <u>Laravel</u> and <u>MySQL</u>. Besides, to work the app at best, it depends on SDK that build using <u>Node</u>, <u>Express</u>, and <u>Mongo</u>, which provides to send single, bulk, schedule messages to whatsapp numbers and so on functionalities.
- Developed a web application, "Hubex", for looking individual process under organization. The backend, built using <u>Node</u>, <u>Express</u>, <u>Mongo</u>, and <u>MySQL</u>, takes advantage of well- developed RESTful API, and user authentication with <u>JWT</u>.
- Developed a web application, "Webinar" using <u>ReactJS</u> and <u>Socket.io</u> that allows users to chat in real time during live video.

- Developed a full-stack web application, "KUAI", using <u>ReactJS</u> that allows users to order foods and so much more. <u>Redux</u> was used to manage state. All data (users, restaurants & miscellaneous) are stored on a backend created using <u>Node</u> and <u>MongoDB</u>.
- Developed a full-stack web application, "tu identidad", using <u>ReactJS</u> that allows users to be a part of an organization and submit various aspects of data such as certificate, address, contact information, stock table for shareholders, etc. <u>Redux</u> was used to manage state. User's all submitted data and progress is stored on a backend created using <u>Node</u> and <u>MongoDB</u>. In addition, there is a chatting feature which allows users to ask for any kind of query.

(Jan. 2019 – Jun. 2019)

Full-Stack Web Developer (Contractual), Door Soft, Dhaka Bangladesh

- Established an already existing website "bdSat" from SAAS to Standalone with contribution of developing new features and fixing existing features' bug, for collecting ISP & Cable TV bills. <u>Bootstrap</u> and <u>jQuery</u> were used to build the front-end. Customers' package, bill and so on data are stored on a back-end using <u>Laravel</u> & <u>MySQL</u>.
- Developed an online platform, "Angel Doctor" for Doctors and Patients.
 Patients can take consultancies and doctors will consult the patients and so more. <u>Bootstrap</u> and <u>jQuery</u> were used to build the front-end. Patients' consultancies and Doctors consultancies' report, payment and so on data are stored on a back- end using <u>Laravel</u> & <u>MySQL</u>.
- Developed a website, "Ask Me POS" that allows Restaurant owners to be a part and grow their food business service. Users can order foods from their desired restaurants and so more. <u>Bootstrap</u> and <u>jQuery</u> was used to build the front-end. Restaurants, Suppliers, Users and so on data are stored on a back-end using <u>Laravel</u> & <u>MySQL</u>.

EDUCATION

2015 - 2019

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering, American International University-Bangladesh

CGPA: 3.55 out of 4.00

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages:

• PHP: Intermediate

• JavaScript: Intermediate

Frameworks:

Laravel: Intermediate
Bootstrap: Intermediate
React: Intermediate
Express.js: Intermediate

Web Technologies:

HTML: Advanced
CSS: Intermediate
jQuery: Intermediate
Ajax: Intermediate
Node: Intermediate
Redux: Intermediate

Programming Languages:

MySQL: IntermediateMongo: Intermediate

Others:

Version Control: Advanced

OOP: IntermediateSDLC: IntermediateUML: Intermediate

REFERENCES

Mahedi Hasan Shuvo, Technical Lead, Workspace Infotech Limited, Dhaka Bangladesh

Email: mahedi@workspaceit.com

Shuvro, Software Engineer, Workspace Infotech Limited, Dhaka Bangladesh

Email: shuvro@workspaceit.com